# ANNE WARIIYU NDUATI

6106-00300, Nairobi · +254748523902 wariiyu.nduati@gmail.com · <u>Anne (Wariiyu) Nduati | LinkedIn · Anne-15 (annie) (github.com)</u>

### **SUMMARY**

**Frontend Engineer (Javascript, React)** with **1+ year** of experience. Passionate and proactive Software Development and UI/UX Product Designer with a strong desire to learn and grow in my career. I possess a creative mindset and enjoy exploring new ideas, solutions, and possibilities. With a keen interest in design, critical thinking and a strategic mindset, I transform ideas and designs to products.

### **PROJECTS**

### **DIABETES MONITORING & MANAGEMENT PLATFORM**

- Developed a mobile application that enables diabetic patients to easily communicate with their healthcare providers.
- Objective: Reduce stigma and facilitate open communication for newly diagnosed patients.
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Flutter, Firebase, Android Phone

Skills: Flutter for android, firebase console, google apis, dart

### **E-COMMERCE PROJECT**

- Developed a web application that provides a single mode of transport for online local stores, minimising delivery costs.
- Working with a backend API technology that connects the user interface and the database
- Predicts the distance of travel using a linear regression model to predict the expected time of travel based on distance given.

Skills: Node JS, React JS & express, TypeScript, TypeORM, Tensorflow, Python, Sklearn, Flask.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER I, TECHNO BRAIN GROUP

[June 2022 - April 2023]

- Triaged daily customer feedback and collaborated with Microsoft to understand customer needs.
- Generated comprehensive daily, monthly, and quarterly review reports.
- Created visually appealing Power BI dashboard reports for data presentation and reports automation.
- Leveraged automation using Microsoft tools to streamline triaging processes.

Skills: critical thinking, power bi, data analysis, powerpoint presentation, Automation

# STUDENT MENTOR, TECHNOVATION SUMMER SCHOOL FOR GIRLS

[February 2022 - July 2022]

Mentored primary school children in building programs and applications using the latest technologies.

Skills: mentorship

# YOUTH LEADER, AIESEC IN UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

[February 2019 - January 2022]

- Managed cash inflows and receipts (2019-2020).
- Created a membership database, conducted engagement surveys, and implemented a rewards and recognition framework for growth and development (2020-2021).
- Managed organisation accounts as Vice President of Finance (2021-2022).

Skills: leadership, team management, event management, finance, talent management

# **EDUCATION**

# BSC. COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

[2018 - 2023]

Undertook a bachelor's degree in computer science with knowledge in the following areas:

 Data structures and algorithms, machine learning, artificial intelligence, computer architecture, software engineering, compiler construction and network & network programming.

# **CODING BOOTCAMPS:**

- Moringa School Introduction to programming (2018)
  - Learnt basic skills in programming and building websites

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- ALX software engineering (2023)
  - Developed solutions in both front-end and back-end technologies

Skills: HTML, CSS, API development, Databases, Flask, Python.

# **SKILLS**

JavaScript, Python, API development, Databases and Storage - SQL, ORM, ReactJS, NodeJS, Flask, Critical thinking, Leadership, UI/UX design.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Google Cloud Platform, AWS machine learning introduction, Leadership, UI/UX Design